A Finding Aid to the Holger Cahill Papers, 1910-1993, bulk 1910-1960, in the Archives of American Art AAA.cahiholg
Archives of American Art
- Works Progress Administration Federal Art Project, 1934-1970; Series 3; (Boxes 2-14, 18, MMs009; 10.75 linear ft.)
  - General Subjects, circa 1934-1943, 1953; 3.1
    - Report, National WPA/FAP: Summary and Recommendations for Continuation, 1939 (Reel 1105, Frame 0975-1086)
    - WPA/FAP and Negro Art, 1938-1943 (Reel 1105, Frame 0616-0635)
    - WPA/FAP, Criticism of, 1936-1943 (Reel 1105, Frame 0636-0645)
    - WPA/FPA, Support of, 1936-1939, undated; (1 of 2) (Reel 1108, Frame 0939-0941)
    - WPA/FPA, Support of, 1936-1939, undated; (2 of 2) (Reel 1105, Frame 0646-0666)
    - WPA/FPA and War Effort, 1940-1943 (Reel 1105, Frame 0667-0784)
  - Artist Files, 1935-1943; 3.2
    This subseries contains records relating to FAP artists. Correspondence is primarily between Cahill and various artists and includes letters of recommendation written by Cahill. General records include a typescript of an interview with Edith Halpert of Downtown Galleries, a document containing case studies on the "Adjustments of Individuals" during FAP work in Michigan; and printed material. A notebook entitled "Artists Whose Loan Assignments Have Been Completed," records "loans" of artists to various states and cities in order to work on FAP projects.
    All individual artist files contain a biographical sketch of the artist, unless otherwise noted. Some files also contain photographs of the artist, as indicated.
    - Artist Files, Correspondence, 1935-1943 (Reel 1107, Frame 0038-0098)
    - Artist Files, General Records, 1935-1943 (Reel 1107, Frame 0001-0021)
    - Artist Files, Lists of Artists and Works, 1938-1941 (Reel 5287, Frame 1173-1266)
    - Artist Files, Notebook "Artists Whose Loan Assignments Have Been Completed,", 1938-1939 (Reel 1107, Frame 0099-0157)
    - Abbott, Berenice, undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1268-1270)
    - Barela, Patrocino, circa 1935; (resume) (Reel 1107, Frame 0022-0026)
    - Bennett, Gwendolyn, undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1271-1272)
    - Bird, Elzy J., undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1273-1274)
    - Brown, Samuel J., undated; (includes photo of Brown) (Reel 5287, Frame 1275-1279)
    - Bufano, Beniamino, undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1280-1284)
    - Bufano, Beniamino, 1941; (catalog) (Reel 1107, Frame 0027-0037)
    - Cervantez, Pedro, undated; (includes photo of Cervantez) (Reel 5287, Frame 1285-1287)
    - Curtis, Phillip C., undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1288-1289)
    - Evergood, Philip, 1939; (includes photo of Evergood) (Reel 5287, Frame 1290-1292)
    - Gershoy, Eugenie, undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1293-1294)
    - Gettens, Rutherford J., undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1295-1296)
    - Gorky, Arshile, undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1297-1298)
    - Gregory, Waylande, undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1299-1303)
    - Guglielmi, Louis, undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1304-1305)
    - Hiler, Hilaire, undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1306-1307)
    - Hord, Donal, undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1308-1309)
    - Hunter, R. Vernon, undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1310-1311)
    - Jacobi, Eli, undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1312-1313)
    - Knaths, Karl, undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1314-1315)
    - Kopman, Benjamin, undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1316-1318)
    - Macdonald-Wright, Stanton, undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1319-1322)
    - Murray, Hester Miller, undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1323-1325)
    - Newell, James Michael, undated; (includes photo of Newell) (Reel 5287, Frame 1326-1329)
    - Olds, Elizabeth, undated; (includes photo of Olds) (Reel 5287, Frame 1330-1333)
    - Palo-Kangas, John, undated; (includes photo of Palo-Kangas) (Reel 5287, Frame 1334-1336)
    - Park, Paul, undated; (includes photo of Park) (Reel 5287, Frame 1337-1338)
    - Quirt, Walter, undated; (includes phot of Quirt) (Reel 5287, Frame 1339-1343)
    - Rourke, Constance, undated (Reel 5287, Frame 1344-1345)
    - Segal, George, undated; (photo of Segal only; see also Box 18) (Reel 5287, Frame 1346-1348)
    - Seltzer, Leo, undated; (photo of Seltzer only) (Reel 5287, Frame 1349-1351)
    - Siporin, Mitchell, undated; (includes photo of Siporin) (Reel 5287, Frame 1352-1357)
    - Sommer, William, undated; (includes photo of Sommer) (Reel 5287, Frame 1358-1362)
    - Speck, Walter E., undated; (includes photo of Speck) (Reel 5287, Frame 1363-1368)
    - Sutton, Harry H., undated; (includes photo of Sutton) (Reel 5287, Frame 1369-1372)
    - Trentham Eugene, undated; (typescript by and photo of Trentham) (Reel 5287, Frame 1373-1377)
    - Velonis, Anthony, undated; (includes photo of Velonis) (Reel 5287, Frame 1378-1382)
    - Viviano, Emmanuel, undated; (includes photo of Viviano) (Reel 5287, Frame 1383-1386)
    - Ward, Lynd, 1939; (includes photo of Ward) (Reel 5287, Frame 1387-1390)
    - Weisenborn, Rudolph, undated; (includes photo of Weisenborn) (Reel 5287, Frame 1391-1395)
    - White, Francis Robert, undated; (includes photo of White) (Reel 5287, Frame 1396-1399)
    - Wolff, Robert Jay, undated; (includes photo of Wolff) (Reel 5287, Frame 1400-1404)
  - Administration of the National WPA/FAP, 1935-1942; 3.3
    This subseries includes detailed financial records, memoranda, organizational charts and plans, and reports documenting the administration of the FAP at the national level.
    A file relating to the 1939 changeover includes a typescript by George Biddle, Memorandum on a Post-War Reorganization of the Section of Fine Arts and Other Federal Art Projects, and a reprint of Art Under Five Years of Federal Patronage, also by Biddle.
    Reports consist pimarily of progress reports provided by Cahill and Thomas C. Parker in addition to several general reports written by Cahill, scattered field trip reports, and miscellanous documents providing general accounts of the activities of the FAP.
    General memoranda and program descriptons contain questionnaire results, descriptions of FAP programs, typescripts containing general program descriptions (possibly given as speeches or issued as press releases), and related news clippings.
    Summaries of WPA art programs includes five copies of a document, "The WPA Art Program - A Summary," with hand-written notations updating the information in the Summary through 1942.
    - 1939 Changeover and After, 1939-1942 (Reel 1106, Frame 0113-0210)
    - Financial Records, Vouchers for Per Diem, 1942 (Reel 1105, Frame 0154-0249)
    - Financial Records, Vouchers for Per Diem, 1942-1943 (Reel 1105, Frame 0250-0280)
    - Financial Reports, Allotments and Encumberances, 1936-1937 (Reel 1106, Frame 0319-0333)
    - Financial Reports, Analysis of Expenditures, 1935-1943 (Reel 1106, Frame 0358-0389)
    - Financial Reports, Financial Summaries, 1936-1939 (Reel 1106, Frame 0390-0394)
    - Financial Reports, State Directors of Finance and Statistics, 1937 (Reel 1106, Frame 0356-0357)
    - Financial Reports, Status of Art Project, 1936 (Reel 1106, Frame 0334-0355)
    - Memoranda, 25% Non-Relief Exemptions, 1935-1936 (Reel 1106, Frame 0001-0112)
    - Memoranda, General, and Program Descriptions, 1936-1940 (Reel 1105, Frame 1171-1328)
    - Memoranda, Sponsorship, 1937 (Reel 1106, Frame 0306-0318)
    - Organization Charts, circa 1938 (Reel 1105, Frame 1088-1092)
    - Organization Plan, 1938 (Reel 1105, Frame 1093-1170)
    - Reports, 1936-1937 (Reel 1105, Frame 1329-1446)
    - Reports, 1937 (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0560-0568)
    - Reports, 1939 (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0504-0508)
    - Reports, 1937-1940 (Reel 1105, Frame 1447-1552)
    - Summaries of WPA Art Programs, 1940-1942 (Reel 1106, Frame 0211-0305)
  - Administration of the State WPA/FAP, 1935-1943; 3.4
    This subseries contains records documenting the adminstration of the FAP at the state level. It includes general correspondence and memoranda regarding state activities as well as reports of state program operations and accomplishments, field trip reports, and newsletters and bulletins from state art centers organized alphabetically by state.
    This subseries contains a second set of state studies which, in addition to administrative reports, includes reports representing research and writing conducted as part of the FAP work done at the state level. The second group of reports is also arranged alphabetically by state, and then chronologically, and includes social studies conducted by members of the Federal Writers Program.
    - Correspondence, 1935-1940 (Reel 1106, Frame 0395-0417)
    - Field Trip Reports, 1935 (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0804-0807)
    - Lists of State and Regional Directors, circa 1935-1936 (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0808-0821)
    - Memoranda to State and Regional Directors, 1935-1936 (Reel 1105, Frame 0127-0145)
    - Memoranda to State and Regional Directors, 1937 (Reel 1105, Frame 0104-0126)
    - Memoranda to State and Regional Directors, 1938 (Reel 1105, Frame 0076-0103)
    - Memoranda to State and Regional Directors, 1939 (Reel 1105, Frame 0065-0075)
    - Memoranda to State and Regional Directors, Requisitioned Material, 1936 (Reel 1105, Frame 0146-0153)
    - Midwest Mural Competition, undated (Reel 5290, Frame 0506-0516)
    - California, undated (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0978-0989)
    - California, circa 1935-1937 (Reel 1106, Frame 0418-0513)
    - Florida, circa 1936 (Reel 1106, Frame 0514-0522)
    - Illinois, 1936 (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0862-0865)
    - Illinois, 1940 (Reel 1106, Frame 0523-0530)
    - Iowa, 1936 (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0859-0861)
    - Iowa, circa 1937 (Reel 1106, Frame 0531-0537)
    - Kansas, 1935 (Reel 1106, Frame 0538-0540)
    - Kansas, 1936 (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0854-0858)
    - Minnesota, undated (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0532-0538)
    - Minnesota, 1939 (Reel 1106, Frame 0541-0550)
    - Minnesota, 1943 (Reel 1106, Frame 0554-0562)
    - Missouri, 1935 (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0539-0557)
    - Missouri, 1942 (Reel 1106, Frame 0551-0553)
    - New York City, 1935-1943 (Reel 1106, Frame 0563-0594)
    - New York State, 1937-1938 (Reel 1107, Frame 0701-0737)
    - North Carolina, 1936 (Reel 1106, Frame 595)
    - Oregon, 1940 (Reel 1106, Frame 0596-0601)
    - Pennsylvania, circa 1935-1940 (Reel 1106, Frame 0602-0612)
    - Texas, 1935 (Reel 1106, Frame 0613-0617)
    - Virginia, 1936 (Reel 1106, Frame 0618-0625)
    - Wyoming, 1937 (Reel 1106, Frame 0626-0654)
    - Arizona, The Phoenix Art Center by Morsell, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0364-0372)
    - California, [ Young California Artists] by Morsell for Parnassus, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0373-0377)
    - California, The Hand-Writing on the Walls by Homer W. Evans, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0378-0389)
    - California, The Study of Early American Wall Painting in Southern California by Warren W. Lemmon, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0390-0400)
    - California, Redwood Sculpture on the Federal Art Project, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0401-0402)
    - California, Children's Art Classes by Vivian Swelander, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0403-0409)
    - California, An Exhibition for Artists and Layman Behind the Scenes in Making a Mosaic, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0410-0413)
    - California, An Exhibition That Graphically Demonstrates the Use of Art in Public Buildings, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 414)
    - California, Aquatic Park Exhibition, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0415-0422)
    - California, [ Beniamino Bufano], undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0423-0425)
    - California, Sculpture Produced on Federal Art Project of the WPA, California, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0426-0427)
    - California, Southern California Creates, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0428-0455)
    - California, Federal Art Project, Los Angeles Museum, 1936 (Reel 5289, Frame 0457-0461)
    - California, [ Federal Art Project], 1936 (Reel 5289, Frame 0462-0465)
    - California, Report from the Northern California Project, circa 1937 (Reel 5289, Frame 472)
    - California, Transcript of Interview Was There A Mission Style of Design? with Frank Freidel and Warren W. Lemmon, 1937 (Reel 5289, Frame 0466-0471)
    - California, Folk Arts in California From 1769 to 1846 by Marjorie Evelyn De Bord, 1938 (Reel 5289, Frame 0473-0555)
    - California, Federal Art Project Reviews Accomplishment, 1938 (Reel 5289, Frame 0556-0557)
    - California, Untitled, circa 1938 (Reel 5289, Frame 558)
    - California, Calfornia's Medical Story in Fresco, 1939 (Reel 5289, Frame 0559-0574)
    - California, Historical Murals in the Los Angeles County Hall of Records Board of Supervisors Hearing Room, 1939 (Reel 5289, Frame 0575-0601)
    - California, Southern California Art Project, Los Angeles Museum, 1939 (Reel 5289, Frame 0602-0611)
    - California, Federal Art Project, [1940] (Reel 5289, Frame 0612-0616)
    - California, Southern California Art Project, 1942 (Reel 5289, Frame 0617-0629)
    - District of Columbia, The Works Program, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0630-0634)
    - District of Columbia, National Exhibit of Children's Art, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0635-0638)
    - District of Columbia, The Federal Art Project: A Summary, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0639-0644)
    - Florida, Autobiographical Sketch by Eve Alsman Fuller, 1936 (Reel 5289, Frame 0645-0648)
    - Florida, Financial Report of Federal Art Galleries of Florida, 1936 (Reel 5289, Frame 0649-0650)
    - Florida, Jacksonville WPA Art Center Brochure, 1942 (Reel 5289, Frame 0651-0658)
    - Florida, Report on the History of the FAP in Florida, 1942 (Reel 5289, Frame 0659-0707)
    - Illinois, Cotton Mather by M. R. Bevier, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0708-0724)
    - Illinois, The Centennial Exposition of 1876 by Helen Sikuta, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0725-0806)
    - Illinois, Early Clockmakers in the United States by Oscar Bluhme, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0807-0823)
    - Illinois, Swiss in Chicago Prior to 1900 by Albert Rudin, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0824-0828)
    - Illinois, Polish Emmigration by Stanley Mazur, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0829-0849)
    - Illinois, English Settlement, Edwards County, Illinois, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0850-0854)
    - Illinois, Moravian Brethren by Helen Sikuta, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0855-0883)
    - Illinois, Early Textiles of the Mormon Pioneers by E. J. Bird, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0884-0886)
    - Illinois, Notes on Coverlets, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0887-0897)
    - Illinois, Early American Copper, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0898-0901)
    - Illinois, Mural America by Increase Robinson, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0902-0917)
    - Illinois, Applied Arts Report, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0918-0958)
    - Illinois, Bishop Hill Paintings by Archie Thompson, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 0985-0988)
    - Illinois, Bishop Hill Colony by Ingegerd Linden, circa 1936 (Reel 5289, Frame 0970-0984)
    - Illinois, Bishop Hill Biographies by Unidentified Author, circa 1936 (Reel 5289, Frame 0989-1008)
    - Illinois, Bishop Hill, Illinois, 1936; (includes 5 photos of the town) (Reel 5289, Frame 0961-0969)
    - Illinois, Suggestions For Material and Its Location in Illinois, 1936 (Reel 5289, Frame 1010-1016)
    - Illinois, WPA Sculptors Lift Chisels to a 2 1/2 Hour Day, Press Digest, August 19, 1936 (Reel 5289, Frame 1017)
    - Illinois, Condensed Statistical Report Covering Mural Project in Illinois, October 27, 1936 (Reel 5289, Frame 1018)
    - Illinois, Stencilled Walls by William L. Warren, 1937 (Reel 5289, Frame 0959-0960)
    - Illinois, Bishop's Hill by Holger Cahill, 1941 (Reel 5289, Frame 1009)
    - Illinois, Project Officials Hail Illinois Art Show at Federal Gallery, February 15, 1938 (Reel 5289, Frame 1019-1022)
    - Illinois, The Illinois Art Project, [1939] (Reel 5289, Frame 1023-1029)
    - Illinois, Baseball In Old Chicago, 1939 (Reel 5289, Frame 1030-1070)
    - Illinois, Millar's Chicago Letter, 1940 (Reel 5289, Frame 1071-1082)
    - Iowa, A Guide to Dubuque, 1937 (Reel 5289, Frame 1083-1103)
    - Iowa, [ Sioux City Community Federal Art Center], 1938 (Reel 5289, Frame 1104-1114)
    - Iowa, Information and Reports on the Two Hemisphere Band Chariot, 1938 (Reel 5289, Frame 1115-1143)
    - Louisiana, Report by Gideon T. Stanton, undated; (1 of 2) (Reel 5289, Frame 1144-1146)
    - Louisiana, Report by Gideon T. Stanton, undated; (2 of 2) (Reel 5289, Frame 1149-1152)
    - Louisiana, Statement by Dr. Robert E. Plunkett, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 1147-1148)
    - Louisiana, New Orleans: What To See, How To See It, 1935 (Reel 5289, Frame 1153-1154)
    - Louisiana, Afton Villa, 1935 (Reel 5289, Frame 1155-1163)
    - Louisiana, Report of Federal Art Project of Louisiana as of, May 1, 1939 (Reel 5289, Frame 1164-1169)
    - Michigan, Untitled Report, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 1170-1184)
    - Michigan, Michigan School for the Blind Receives Sculpture by WPA Artists, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 1185)
    - Michigan, Lincoln by Samuel Cashwan, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 1186)
    - Michigan, The Puppets of the Lano Family, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 1187-1189)
    - Michigan, Fredenthal Murals in the Detroit Naval Armory, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 1190-1192)
    - Michigan, Edgar Yaeger's Murals in the Detroit Naval Armory, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 1193-1194)
    - Michigan, Royal Oak High School Receives Mural Panel by the Makielski Brothers, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 1195-1196)
    - Michigan, Exhibition Press Releases, Index of American Design, 1937-1938 (Reel 5289, Frame 1197-1201)
    - Michigan, Report on Art Projects for Unemployment Relief in Michigan, 1935-1942 by Paul McPharlin (Reel 5289, Frame 1202-1237)
    - Minnesota, Minnesota Artist, 1939 (Reel 5289, Frame 1238-1251)
    - Minnesota, [ Walker Art Center], 1940 (Reel 5289, Frame 1252-1283)
    - Missouri, Press Release, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 1284-1289)
    - Missouri, People's Art Service Center, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 1290-1292)
    - Missouri, Work Projects Administration Service Division - Missouri, Accomplishment Report, February 1, 1943 (Reel 5289, Frame 1293-1335)
    - Nebraska, Nebraska Folklore: Pioneer Recollections, 1940 (Reel 5289, Frame 1336-1349)
    - New Jersey, Program Operation Report, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 1350-1360)
    - New Jersey, The Williamsburg Housing and Newark Airport Projects by Burgoyne Diller, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 1361-1362)
    - New Mexico, Spanish Colonial Arts in New Mexico by R. Vernon Hunter, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 1363-1380)
    - New York, American Artists Face the Future, undated (Reel 5289, Frame 1381-1395)
    - New York, Statistical Report of the Art Teaching Project, 1936 (Reel 5289, Frame 1396)
    - New York, Federal Art Centers of New York, circa 1938 (Reel 5289, Frame 1414-1433)
    - New York, A Community Art Center for Harlem, circa 1938 (Reel 5289, Frame 1434-1445)
    - New York, Recent Prints Available for Allocation, circa 1938 (Reel 5289, Frame 1446-1454)
    - New York, Descriptions of Paintings from the Art and Psychopathology Exhibition, 1938 (Reel 5289, Frame 1397-1413)
    - New York, Free Guided Tours, 1938 (Reel 5289, Frame 1455-1458)
    - New York, Art Work in Non-Federal Buildings and the Federal Art Project of the City of New York, circa 1939 (Reel 5289, Frame 1459-1473)
    - New York, Art Caravan Report, April-May 1939 (Reel 5289, Frame 1474-1488)
    - New York, Art Caravan Report, cont., April-May 1939; (includes photos of Art Caravan) (Reel 5290, Frame 0004-0077)
    - New York, Art Caravan Report, June-August 1939; (includes photos of Art Caravan) (Reel 5290, Frame 0078-0161)
    - New York, Record of Program Operation and Accomplishment, 1943 (Reel 5290, Frame 0162-0185)
    - North Carolina, The WPA and Winston-Salem Art Center, undated (Reel 5290, Frame 0186-0189)
    - North Carolina, Manual of Operation and Procedure of North Carolina Federal Art Projects, 1936-1937 (Reel 5290, Frame 0190-0209)
    - North Carolina, Report on the Preservation of Mountain Culture in Great Smoky Mountains National Park by Dr. Hans Huth, 1941 (Reel 5290, Frame 0210-0244)
    - Ohio, Cleveland Museum of Art, Eductional Work with High Schools, circa 1933 (Reel 5290, Frame 0245-0249)
    - Ohio, Cleveland Museum of Art, Educational Functions of an Art Museum, 1933 (Reel 5290, Frame 0250-0253)
    - Ohio, Cleveland Museum of Art, Museum Educational Work for the General Public, 1939 (Reel 5290, Frame 0254-0256)
    - Ohio, Cleveland Museum of Art, The Art Museum and the Secondary School, circa 1940 (Reel 5290, Frame 0257-0267)
    - Ohio, Cleveland Museum of Art, Visual Material Available for Use in Secondary Schools, 1940 (Reel 5290, Frame 0268-0312)
    - Ohio, Cleveland Museum of Art, Report on Work with Shaker Heights Secondary Schools, 1940 (Reel 5290, Frame 0313-0398)
    - Oklahoma, Record of Program Operation and Accomplishment, undated (Reel 5290, Frame 0399-0405)
    - Oklahoma, Report by Nan Sheets, 1936; (includes photo of Sheets) (Reel 5290, Frame 0406-0409)
    - Oregon, Report on Salem Federal Art Center, undated (Reel 5290, Frame 0410-0421)
    - Oregon, Art in Timberline Lodge by E. J. Griffith, undated (Reel 5290, Frame 0422-0423)
    - Oregon, The Problem of Gallery Attendants by Charles Val Clear, undated (Reel 5290, Frame 0424-0429)
    - Oregon, WPA Community Art Centers, undated (Reel 5290, Frame 0430-0435)
    - Pennsylvania, Report on the Subject of Ornamental Cast Iron in Philadelphia in the First Half of the 19th Century by Katherine Milhous, 1936 (Reel 5290, Frame 0436-0455)
    - Pennsylvania, The Harmony Society in Pennsylvania, 1937 (Reel 5290, Frame 0456-0476)
    - Pennsylvania, Defense Work in Progress, 1941 (Reel 5290, Frame 0477-0478)
    - Virginia, Memoranda on Community Art Centers, circa 1938 (Reel 5290, Frame 0479-0504)
    - Washington State, Bulletin of the Spokane Art Center, 1939 (Reel 5290, Frame 0517-0525)
    - Wisconsin, Artist Who Painted Pope Pius XI Makes Show Place of Old Barn, undated (Reel 5290, Frame 0527-0530)
    - Wisconsin, Miscellaneous Publicity and Notes from Press Digest, 1937, undated (Reel 5290, Frame 0531-0534)
    - Wisconsin, Notes on and Statements by Wisconsin Artists, 1939 (Reel 5290, Frame 0535-0545)
    - Wisconsin, Record of Program Operation and Accomplishment, 1942 (Reel 5290, Frame 0546-0574)
    - Wyoming, A Review of the Federal Art Galleries in Wyoming by E. E. Lowry, 1938 (Reel 5290, Frame 0575-0582)
  - Meeting Minutes and Transcripts, 1936-1941; 3.5
    This subseries contains minutes and transcripts of WPA/FAP meetings and conferences, arranged chronologically.
    - Planning Program of Work and Travel Conference, undated (Reel 1105, Frame 0553-0556)
    - Regional and State Directors Conference, September 1936 (Reel 1105, Frame 0533-0541)
    - Fogg Museum Meeting, January 20, 1938 (Reel 5288, Frame 0003-0026)
    - Federal Art Directors Conference, Washington, D.C., May 1938 (Reel 5292, Frame 0404-0440)
    - Annual Meeting of the American Handicraft Council, February 1940 (Reel NDA 15, Frame 0990-0994)
    - Community Service Projects Meeting, May 21-23, 1940 (Reel 1105, Frame 0518-0532)
    - Community Service Projects Meeting, May 29, 1940 (Reel 5288, Frame 0048-0051)
    - Art Supervisors Conference, Washington, D.C., January 1941 (Reel 5288, Frame 0052-0064)
    - Conference on the Arts Program of the WPA, Transcript, Part 1, October-November 1941 (Reel 1105, Frame 0785-0866)
    - Conference on the Arts Program of the WPA, Transcript, Part 2, October-November 1941 (Reel 1105, Frame 0867-0904)
    - Conference on the Arts Program of the WPA, Transcript, Part 3, October-November 1941 (Reel 1105, Frame 0905-0974)
  - Allocations, 1935-1943, 1970; 3.6
    This subseries documents financial allotments for the FAP program on a national and state level. It contains chronologically arranged correspondence and memoranda showing total allocations and containing lists breaking down allotments by state, as well as general correspondence related to allocations.